NICLAUSS LUMORING

Jakarta, Indonesia | +62-8515-6883-552 | <u>linkedin</u> | <u>gmail</u> | <u>github</u> | medium | portofolio

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am an undergraduate student majoring in Computer Science and Mathematics at Bina Nusantara, with a strong foundation in software development and mathematical problem-solving. My diverse work experiences include teaching programming, customer service, pool management, and mentoring, showcasing my excellent communication, teamwork, and problem-solving skills. Additionally, my background in data science and computer science equips me with the technical skills needed for various technical roles, making me well-prepared to excel in different industries.

EDUCATION

Bina Nusantara (BINUS) Jakarta, Indonesia

Computer Science and Mathematics / Cumulative GPA: 3.54/4.00

Sept 2019 - present

- **Award:** Entry Fee Scholarship (100% of total entry fee)
- Relevant Courses: Algorithm and Programming, Programming Language Concept, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Program Design Method, Scientific Computing Lab, Human and Computer Interaction, Database Systems, Algorithm Design Analysis, Operating System, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Network, Mathematics Programming, Advanced Object Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, Probability and Statistics, Mathematical Statistic I, Mathematical Statistic II, Real Analysis, Actuarial Mathematics, Computer Vision, Cryptography, Computational Geometry, Compilation Technique, Coding Theory
- Laboratory Experience: C Language, Java Programming, Web Programming (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), SQL, Python, Computer Vision, Cryptography

MySkill Jakarta, Indonesia

Intensive Bootcamp Data Science Participant / Certificate

Dec 2022 - Feb 2023

Relevant Courses: Data Science, SQL, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Python, Machine Learning

RevoU Mini Course: Introduction to Data Analytics

Jakarta, Indonesia

Oct 2022

Participant

Learn about data analytics tools, scope of work, and got the basic knowledge of it.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT. Lab Inovasi Teknologi

Jakarta, Indonesia

Freelance Coding and Robotics Teacher | Website Developer

Sept 2023 – Present

- Developed websites, joindeh.com and cyberspace.co.id, for the company utilizing the Tailwind framework based on provided designs in
- Instructed robotics at Bina Bangsa School and HOPE Academy, contributing to the students' understanding of robotics and technology.
- Generated comprehensive reports for the students, ensuring effective communication and documentation of their progress and achievements

PT. Merkle Innovation Jakarta, Indonesia Software Engineer Intern Aug 2023 – Feb 2024

Developed websites, <u>zapelinic.com</u>, for the company utilizing the Tailwind framework based on provided designs in Figma.

PT. Timedoor Indonesia

Jakarta, Indonesia

Coding Tutor

Nov 2022 - Jan 2024

- Teaching students about programming languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Phaser Framework, and other block coding
- Creating a comfortable and fun learning environment.
- Make a report card after the mid and final exams of the curriculum.
- Control and give tutoring assignments to the students.
- Curriculum development learning.

PT. Allianz Life Indonesia

Jakarta, Indonesia

Business Partner

Mar 2020 – Feb 2022

Specialized in health and life assurance and increase group sales recapitulation, financial planner for clients.

PT. Ternak Uang Nusantara

Jakarta, Indonesia

Jakarta, Indonesia

Ternak Uang Squad

Sept – Oct 2021

• Create educational content about the importance of financial literacy.

PT. Fantasia Utama Nuansa (Waterboom) Pool Patrol

June - July 2019

- Explain the mechanism of various rides at Waterboom PIK to visitors.
- Responsible for the safety and comfort of visitors to Waterboom PIK.

Julio and Elsa Bimbel Tutor

Jakarta, Indonesia Sept 2016 – Mar 2019

Taught all courses for students ranging from elementary to senior high school graduates.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE & COLLEGE ACTIVITY

IT Division Training

Jakarta, Indonesia Oct 2019 - Feb 2020

Participant

- Learn about HTML, CSS, JavaScript and work on the project.
- Learn about database and its implementation in SQL Server Management Studio and work on the project.
- Learn about PHP and work on the project.
- Learn about Csharp language and work on the project.
- Learn about MVC Web API and work on the project.
- Learn about Android Studio and work on the project.
- Learn about Binusmaya and work on the project to developing Binusmaya

Final Group Project PHP

Human and Computer Interaction Project

Group Project: "Kenshin Impact" | https://bit.ly/3MQXXuX

Create a web page whose theme is a game called "Kenshin Impact".

Create a homepage, register page, about us page, characters page, news page, gallery page.

Project: "Cloud Broker" | https://bit.ly/3MOUFIr

Tidy up the data given from the UNF form, to 1NF, 2NF, 3NF.

Create an ERD, DML, and DDL

Java Project

Database Project

Project: "Dance Party" | https://bit.ly/3w9IsrV

• Create a menu that must use the OOP concept where in the menu we can add, view, and delete.

Computer Vision Project

Project: "Hand Gesture" | https://bit.ly/3XZCm9n

Developed a Python hand detection module for computer vision projects.

Implemented hand motion recognition for a gesture-based volume control project.

PHP Laravel Project

Project: "Jramedia" | https://bit.ly/30mIa90

Built a PHP and Laravel website for purchasing books and office supplies.

Ensured a secure and seamless checkout process for customers.

Implemented order tracking functionality for easy monitoring of purchases.

Utilized personalized recommendation systems to enhance user experience.

Android Studio Project

Project: "Jsteam" | https://bit.ly/3056xdr

• Developed an Android application named "JSteam" using Android Studio.

JSteam serves as a platform for viewing game lists and providing game reviews.

Includes a feature to display the location of JSteam.

Implemented a secure login verification process, requiring OTP (One-Time Password) for authentication.

Himpunan Matematika BINUS

Main Coordinator of Public Relations

Supervised all the staff of public relations division to do the job.

Lead the divisions to collect data of HIMMAT's members.

Lead the divisions to supervise and handle events.

Lead the academic team from the preparation of the competition to the competition.

Himpunnan Matematika BINUS

Activist

Staff of Publication and Documentation of "ACARA KEBERSAMAAN HIMMAT 2019"

Treasury at "HIMMAT BIRTHDAY 2020"

Staff of Event Organizer at "HIMMAT BIRTHDAY 2021"

Head of Recruiting New Himmat Activists 2021

Public Relations at "Himmat Festival 2021"

Public Relations at "Academic Sharing HIMMAT 2021"

Main Coordinator of Public Relations of HIMMAT 2022/2023

Core Management Board at Himmat 2022

Core of the Question-Making Team at "MATIC 2022"

Bina Nusantara

Freshman Leader and Freshman Partner

Helping freshman know more about BINUS.

Guiding freshman to do the task given from BINUS.

Helping and guiding freshman at the beginning of the semester.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Programming Language Skills: C Language, Java, SQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Tailwind Framework, Block Coding.

Other Skills: Technical Trading, Chart Analysis, Data Science, Fundamental Business Analysis | Computer: Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Adobe, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Dev C++, SQL Server Management Studio, Eclipse Workspace, Jupyter Notebook

Additional Skills: Time management, Leadership, Systematic Planner, Teamwork, Adaptability, Organization, Target-Focused, Critical Thinking Language: Bahasa Indonesia (Native), English, Chinese

Interests: Coding, Books, Editing, Writing, Stock and Currency Trading, Business Fundamental Analysis, Sport

Jakarta, Indonesia

Sept - Oct 2021

Jakarta, Indonesia

June – July 2021

Jakarta, Indonesia

June – July 2021

Jakarta, Indonesia

Jan 2023

Jakarta, Indonesia

May 2023

Jakarta, Indonesia June 2023

Jakarta, Indonesia

Feb 2022 - present

Jakarta, Indonesia

Dec 2019 – present

Jakarta, Indonesia

Aug - Sept 2020